{
	"quiz": [{
			"qnum": 1,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "Java is a(n) ______-oriented programming language",
			"correctAnswer": "object",
			"options": ["object", "subject", "logic", "quadratic"],
			"feedback": "Object-oriented programming (OOP) is a programming paradigm based on the concept of objects, which can contain data and code: data in the form of fields (often known as attributes or properties), and code, in the form of procedures (often known as methods)."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 2,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "Python is a(n) _______ high-level general-purpose programming language.",
			"correctAnswer": "interpreted",
			"options": ["interpolated", "mandated", "interpreted", "object-oriented"],
			"feedback": "An interpreter is a computer program that directly executes instructions written in a programming or scripting language, without requiring them previously to have been compiled into a machine language program."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 3,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "In which platform is Java the most popular language in use?",
			"correctAnswer": "GitHub",
			"options": ["Instagram", "Facebook", "Stack Overflow", "GitHub"],
			"feedback": "Instagram, Facebook are not programming/hosting platforms. Stack Overflow is a programming support site. GitHub is the guy for you."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 4,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "Java syntax is similar to ",
			"correctAnswer": "C.",
			"options": ["Python.", "C.", "Swift", "Ruby"],
			"feedback": "The syntax of Java is similar to C and C++, but has fewer low-level facilities than either of them."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 5,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "Who is the father of the C language?",
			"correctAnswer": "Dennis Ritchie",
			"options": ["Steve Jobs", "Bill Gates", "Mark Zuckerberg", "Dennis Ritchie"],
			"feedback": "A successor to the programming language B, C was originally developed at Bell Labs by Dennis Ritchie between 1972 and 1973 to construct utilities running on Unix."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 6,
			"questionType": "true_false",
			"questionText": "JDK is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs.",
			"correctAnswer": "True",
			"options": ["True","False"],
			"feedback": "The Java Development Kit (JDK), which is intended for software developers and includes development tools such as the Java compiler, Javadoc, Jar, and a debugger."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 7,
			"questionType": "true_false",
			"questionText": "The java file extension is .py",
			"correctAnswer": "False",
			"options": [".class", ".js", ".java", ".txt"],
			"feedback": "That is the file extension for a python file."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 8,
			"questionType": "true_false",
			"questionText": "Python is case sensitive when dealing with identifiers",
			"correctAnswer": "True",
			"options": ["True","False"],
			"feedback": "Python is case sensitive when dealing with identifiers, so they won't get mixed up."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 9,
			"questionType": "true_false",
			"questionText": "Class is a core data type in Python programming.",
			"correctAnswer": "False",
			"options": ["True","False"],
			"feedback": "Class is a user-defined data type."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 10,
			"questionType": "true_false",
			"questionText": "The output of print(math.pow(3, 2)) is 9.0",
			"correctAnswer": "True",
			"options": ["True","False"],
			"feedback": "math.pow() returns a floating number (decimal)."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 11,
			"questionType": "text_input",
			"questionText": "What is the truncation division operator in Python?",
			"correctAnswer": "//",
			"feedback": "// is truncated because it will only display the integer part of the quotient."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 12,
			"questionType": "text_input",
			"questionText": "Type in the output of this: min(max(False,-3,-4), 2,7)",
			"correctAnswer": "False",
			"feedback": "The function max() is being used to find the maximum value from among -3, -4 and false. Since false amounts to the value zero, hence we are left with min(0, 2, 7) Hence the output is 0 (false)."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 13,
			"questionType": "text_input",
			"questionText": "Fill in the blank. The package used for text formatting in Java programming language is java.____",
			"correctAnswer": "text",
			"feedback": "java.text allows formatting, searching and manipulating text."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 14,
			"questionType": "text_input",
			"questionText": "Enter in the complied Java class file extension.",
			"correctAnswer": ".class",
			"feedback": "The compiled java files have .class extension."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 15,
			"questionType": "text_input",
			"questionText": "Enter in which environment variable is used to set the java path.",
			"correctAnswer": "JAVA_HOME",
			"feedback": "JAVA_HOME is used to store a path to the java installation."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 16,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "Which of the following is not a segment of memory in java?",
			"correctAnswer": "Register Segment",
			"options": ["Code Segment","Register Segment","Heap Segment","Stack Segment"],
			"feedback": "There are only 3 types of memory segment. Stack Segment, Heap Segment and Code Segment."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 17,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "Which exception is thrown when java is out of memory?",
			"correctAnswer": "OutOfMemoryError",
			"options": ["OutOfMemoryError","MemoryOutOfBoundsException","MemoryFullException","NoMemoryError"],
			"feedback": "The Xms flag has no default value, and Xmx typically has a default value of 256MB. A common use for these flags is when you encounter a java.lang.OutOfMemoryError."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 18,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java?",
			"correctAnswer": "keyword",
			"options": ["identifier and keyword","identifier","keyword","container"],
			"feedback": "Keywords are specially reserved words that can not be used for naming a user defined variable, for example: class, int, for, etc."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 19,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "Which of the following is a type of polymorphism in Java Programming?",
			"correctAnswer": "Compile time polymorphism",
			"options": ["Multilevel polymorphism","Multiple polymorphism","Execution time polymorphism","Compile time polymorphism"],
			"feedback": "There are two types of polymorphism in Java. Compile time polymorphism (overloading) and runtime polymorphism (overriding)."
		},
		{
			"qnum": 20,
			"questionType": "multiple_choice",
			"questionText": "Which of these coding types is used for data type characters in Java?",
			"correctAnswer": "UNICODE",
			"options": ["ASCII","UNICODE","ISO-LATIN-1","CHEF"],
			"feedback": "Unicode defines fully international character set that can represent all the characters found in all human languages. Its range is from 0 to 65536."
		}


	]

}
